

Fabio Carmelo Maria Viscuso

WEB DEVELOPER, FRONTEND SPECIALIZING IN REACT-BASED WEB APPS

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I'm a passionate and curious web developer, who loves living in the "bleeding edge" and keeping up to date with the latest and greatest in the industry.

My mission is to leave a mark and contribute in delivering awesome web experiences that users love.

I love to write code. But I also love to keep it clean and tidy, reusable and documented. It's not just a skill, it's a testament of love for the project and your colleagues.

SKILLS RECAP

Front-End & Back-End

HTML5, CSS3 (+ Bootstrap, Tailwind), JavaScript ES6+, TypeScript, React (+ Redux Toolkit, Zustand, Router), Next.js 12+. HTML templating engines (ejs, isml), Node.js, Express, SQL, NoSQL, ORM (+ Prisma, Sequelize),

General or non strictly web-related skills

Agile workflow, Git (+ hosting platforms: GitHub, GitLab, BitBucket), basic Linux (+ WSL2), Rust, WebAssembly

CONTACTS

Phone: +39 351 9966 861

E-mail: viscuso.fabio@outlook.it

Address: via Salvo D'Acquisto, 5

95022 - Aci Catena (CT)

Website: fabioviscuso.website

LinkedIn: fabiocarmelomariaviscuso

GitHub: FabioViscuso

WORK EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPMENT INTERNSHIP

Deloitte Digital - Commerce (Nov 2022 - Mag 2023)

Hands-on approach on the Salesforce Commerce Cloud platform. The project I worked on was based on the SFRA, which uses a common stack that comprises

- isml as the HTML templating engine
- CSS (custom SASS + Bootstrap),
- JS ES6, jQuery
- E2E testing with CodeceptJS and Selenium WebDriver.
- Jira and Confluence for tasks management and documentation.

In my day-to-day I contributed to both bugfixing and features integration, especially regarding end-user QoL but also related to business logic and third party integrations.

WEB DEVELOPMENT INTERNSHIP

SEO Tester Online (Nov 2019 - Gen 2021)

First professional experience in the web development industry. Aside from the basic stack, I also learned about:

- Docker
- VirtualBox + Vagrant, Windows Subsystem for Linux 2
- CMS: Magento & WordPress

In the first part of my internship I worked on some sibling e-commerce websites, helping in the bugfixing and refactoring. In the second part I implemented the website for STO's parent company in cooperation with the UI/UX designer. Then I spent the last months In developing a SERP preview tool prototype for internal use.

EDUCATION AND LEARNING

DEVELHOPE

Full-Stack developer course (React + Node.js) (Feb 2022 - Sep 2022)

6-months duration coding bootcamp, focused on learning the following technologies:

- Git, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, React 18 & Redux, TypeScript, Node.js 16+, Express 4, elements of SQL Databases
- Agile/SCRUM Workflow, teamwork and team leadership

Aside from the course, I've explored hosting platforms such as Vercel, Netlify, Heroku, and AWS (RDS service)

UNIVERSITÀ DEGLI STUDI DI CATANIA

Computer Science course - 2 years. without degree Enterprise economics course - 2 years. without degree

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in the application to be processed for the purposes of the recruitment process in accordance with Art. 6 paragraph 1 letter a of the Regulation of the European Parliament and of the Council (EU) 2016/679 of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation).